Guide to the Tamiment Library Manuscript Files TAM.245
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library Manuscript Files
1749-1988
1910-1965
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Barnett, Joshua
Robbins, Sonia Jaffe
Dirk J. (Dirk Jan) Struik, 1894-2000
TAM.245
7.5 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons, 1 manuscript box, and 1 oversized folder
The Tamiment Library, founded in 1906 as the library of the Rand School of Social Science, is a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action. It accumulated this artificial collection of brief manuscript files over the years. The files pertain largely to individuals, and also to organizations, events and topics, and contain correspondence, manuscripts and typescripts, as well as a few items of printed ephemera.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriciton.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this assembled collection were either donated or found in the repository. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 1950.037, 2011.033, 2013.032, 2013.035, 2014.039, and 2014.092.
Existence and Location of Copies
A small number of items are available as photocopies only, with the originals stored in the vault. This is indicated in the folder title.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into one series:
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of brief manuscript files over the course of its early existence. The files pertain largely to individuals, and also to organizations, events and topics, and correspondence, manuscripts and typescripts, as well as some items of printed ephemera. While most of the individuals and organizations were active in the United States, there are also files for a number of prominent European and other foreign figures and organizations represented.
Custodial History
This is an artificially created collection, which was created through several donations over the years. Additionally a 1965 research query from Bernard K. Johnpoll to Universiteit van Amsterdam and a 1975 issue of the "Objector" from the SUNY Albany Committee to End the War in Vietnam were found in the repository and added to the collection in 2014.
Custodial History
The provenance of much of the material is unknown; the bulk of it was given to or generated by staff of the Tamiment Library in its early years, before the Library was transferred.
The materials that comprise Box 8, Folders 17 and 18 were found in the repository and added to the collection in 2014. The accession number associated with these materials is 2014.039.
As of August 2025, box 3, folder 47a ("Hall, Otto: Autobiography (typescript, 12 leave)") is missing.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists largely of correspondence to and from important figures in American and European radical and labor movements, among them Angela Balabanoff, Clarence Darrow, Karl Marx, Eugene V. Debs, Fredrick Engels, J. Keir Hardie, Darlington Hoopes, Samuel Gompers and Leon Trotsky. Some letters from the files of the Tamiment Library to and from researchers are also part of the collection.
Also included in the collection are a significant number of typescripts and manuscripts (some in the form of photocopies) by political and literary figures such as David Ben-Gurion, Earl Browder, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Charlotte Perkins Gilman, Jack London and Mark Twain.
Ephemeral items include a receipt for a payment to V. I. Lenin in Switzerland, two documents from the French Revolution, a manifesto signed by Emiliano Zapata and early nineteenth century British broadsides. Handwritten Russian-language newsletters circulated by Palmer Raid deportees known as the "Ellis Island Bulletins" are also included in the collection.
Communists |z Europe |v Archives.; Communism |z United States |v Sources.; Clippings (information artifacts); Anarchists |z Europe |v Archives.; Anarchism |z United States |v Sources.; Broadsides (notices); Correspondence.; Anarchists |z United States |v Archives.; Manuscripts; Labor leaders |z United States |v Archives.; Minutes (administrative records); Labor unions |z United States |v Sources.; Records (documents); Socialism |z United States |v Sources.; Typescripts; Socialists |z United States |v Archives.; Beard, Charles A. (Charles Austin), 1874-1948; Ben-Gurion, David, 1886-1973; Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (Mary Eleanor), 1877-1955; Berger, Victor L., 1860-1929; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951; American Labor Party; American Workers Party. Provisional Organizing Committee; Hillquit, Morris, 1869-1933; Sugar, Maurice, 1891-1974; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983.; Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989; Hardie, James Keir, 1856-1915; Germer, Adolph; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973; Ghent, William J. (William James), 1866-1942; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982.; Georgia People's School; Gerber, Julius, 1862-1916; Fleischman, Harry; Kerensky, Aleksandr Fyodorovich, 1881-1970; International Socialist Congress; Hourwich, Isaac A. (Isaac Aaronovich), 1860-1924; International Socialist Club; Hoopes, Darlington, 1896-; Continental Congress of Workers and Farmers for Economic Reconstruction; Commonwealth Federation of New York; Colón, Jesús, 1901-; Carey, James B.; Ward, Henry Frederick, 1873-1966.; Fischer, Ruth, 1895-; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963; Dodd, Bella V., 1904-1969; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; Debs Meeting Committee; Dan, F. (Fedor), 1871-1947; Crosswaith, Frank Rudolph, 1892-1965; Powderly, Terence Vincent, 1849-1924.; Poyntz, Julia Stuart, 1886-1937?; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970; Rocker, Rudolf, 1873-1958.; Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee; Sacco-Vanzetti National League; Sacco-Vanzetti New Trial League; Sanial, L. (Lucien), 1836-; Co-operative League of America; Schneiderman, Rose, 1882-1972; Shiplacoff, A. I. (Abraham Isaac), 1877-1936; Shub, David, 1887-1973; Josephson, Ben, 1895-1980; Silone, Ignazio, 1900-1978; South Slavonian Socialist Industry League; Stamm, Thomas; Kuczynski, Jurgen; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Laski, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950; Lawyers Committee on American Relations With Spain; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942; Matthews, J. B. (Joseph Brown), 1894-1966; Mutual Society of Journeymen Cabinet Makers, of the City of New-York; Moyer, Charles H.; National Maritime Union of America; Billings, Warren K., 1893-1972; National Education Committee for a New Party; Andrews, John B. (John Bertram), 1880-1943; Bohn, William E.; O'Connor, Harvey, 1897-1987; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965; People's College (Fort Scott, Kan.); Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Laundry Workers International Union; Wolfe, Bertram David, 1896-1977.; Lee, Algernon; Wilkerson, Doxey Alphonso, 1905-1993.; Van Kleeck, Mary, 1883-; Zucker, Abraham.; Workers Education Bureau of America; Woll, Matthew, 1880-1956.; Barnett, Joshua; Robbins, Sonia Jaffe; Dirk J. (Dirk Jan) Struik, 1894-2000
- Adamic, Louis: Correspondence (to Industrial Union League), Dec 16, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Affiliated Summer Schools for Women Workers in Industry: Correspondence and Manuscript, Mar 5, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AFL-CIO: Bibliography on AFL-CIO Merger (Tamiment Library, typescript), ca.1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Amalgamated Association of Street, Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America, Division 994 (AFL): Appeal for Fired Fifth Avenue Coach Men, May 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America: Staff Information, Speech, Manuscript (Richard Rohman, Publicity Director), 1935, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Amalgamated Sheet Metal Workers International Alliance: Elections and Personnel, Oct 15, 1913, Jan 24, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- American Conference on National and Racial Unity, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Federation of Austrian Democrats: Flyer for Anti-Fascist Meeting, New York City (German language), Mar 11, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7a)
- American Labor Committee to Aid British Labor: Press Release, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Labor Party: Constitution and Correspondence (correspondents include August Claessens, John Gelo, William Karlin, Nathaniel Minkoff, Charles Solomon and Mark Starr), 1934-1956 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- American Labor Party, New York State: Correspondence (correspondents include Herbert Lehman, Marx Lewis, Mark Starr and Pearl L. Willen), 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- American Legion: Bibliography on the World Communist Movement and Firing Line(newsletter), 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- American Student Union: Report to the New England District Committee [CPUSA], Oct 14, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11A)
- American Workers Party Provisional Organizing Committee: Minutes, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Andreas, Bert (Researcher): Correspondence re: Marx and Engels, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Andrews, John B: Correspondence (correspondents include C.L. James, Emma Goldman, Vincent St. John, Joseph A. Labadie, William Bailie, William T. Holmes and Elizabeth Gurley Flynn), 1906-1908 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Andrews, John B: Manuscripts, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Anti-Imperialist League of New York: Correspondence (Williams Simmons, J. Bruno), outgoing, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Association of Catholic Trade Unionists: History (typescript), undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Balabanoff, Angela: Correspondence to Harold Reisman, Sidney Hook, Mar 15, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Baltimore Labor College, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Barondess, Joseph: Letter to D. Bernberg, Apr 10, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Basseches, Nikolai: Correspondence and Manuscripts (German language), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Beard, Charles: Correspondence to William Bohn, [1934] (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Bein, Albert: "Let Freedom Ring" (play script), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Bellamy, Ralph: Letter to Louise Heinze, Feb 14, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Belsky, Abe: Correspondence (outgoing), 1941-1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Ben-Gurion, David. Labor Zionism(New York: Young Poale Zion Alliance), 5 leaves (mimeograph), undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Berger, Victor L.: Correspondence (Herman Schleuter and George Goebel), Jun 4, 1912, May 14, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Berger, Victor L.: "The First Socialist in the United States Congress: The Story of His Work in Congress as Told by the Press", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Besant, Sir Walter: Correspondence (incoming and outgoing), 1884-1900 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Billings, Warren K.: Correspondence, Billings Victory Ball Program, 1922-1939 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Bittelman, Alex: Correspondence (Abe Magil), 1960-1961, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Blake, Eleanor: "Elementary Lessons in Social Science" (typescript, 67 leaves), undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Blanc, Louis: Letter to "Mon cher Monsieur", Apr 16, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Blanshard, Paul: Correspondence (Socialist Party Resignation), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Blatchford, Robert: "Merrie England" (Yiddish translation by Herman Dubrowitz; manuscript) (I), undated (Box 1, Folder 34A)
- Blatchford, Robert: "Merrie England" (Yiddish translation by Herman Dubrowitz; manuscript) (II), undated (Box 1, Folder 34B)
- Blatchford, Robert: "Merrie England" (Yiddish translation by Herman Dubrowitz; manuscript) (III), undated (Box 1, Folder 34C)
- Blume, Bernard: "In the Name of the People" (play script), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Blumenberg, Werner: Research Materials, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Bogard, Thomas J. (member of the Industrial Workers of the World, Democratic Party activist): Correspondence, Personal Papers, 1936-1958 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Bohn, William E.: Correspondence (correspondents include Carl Sandburg), Manuscripts, 1932-1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Bombay Textile Labour Union. "Labour Representation Submitted to the Indian Tariff Board (Cotton Textile Enquiry) and the Union's Replies to the Board's Questionnaire", 1926 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Boston Conference on Socialism (Feb 5-7, 1909): Correspondence (correspondents include Franklin H. Giddings, Walter Rauschenbusch, Vida D. Scudder, Emily G. Balch, Cerise Carmen Jack), Program, 1908-1909 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Bourguina, Anna: "Enslavement of Culture in Soviet Russia" (typescript, 31 leaves; Russian language), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Bowers, Florence W. "Essay on Honesty, and a Salute to the Brave…" (typescript, 4 leaves, Anti-Communist leftist re the failings of some ex-Communists), 1940 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Braden, Carl: Letter to "Brother Singer", Oct 3, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Bray, John: Bibliographies, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Broadside no. 134 of the Paris Commune: Report on the defense of Paris, Apr 1871 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS001, Folder 1)
- Broadside no. 140 of the Paris Commune: Federation des Artistes de Paris, Apr 1871 (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS001, Folder 1)
- Broun, Heywood: Correspondence (William Dunne), Sep 20, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Browder, Earl: "Trotzykism and World Peace: Speech of Earl Browder, General Secretary of the Communist Party at Madison Square Garden, Feb. 5, 1937." (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Browder, Earl: The Writings and Speeches of Earl Browder(unbound mimeograph collection), May 24, 1945-Jul 26, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Brown, Emily N.: Manuscripts (Workmen's Compensation in New York State), 1913, ca.1932, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Cahan, Abraham: Correspondence (outgoing), 1918, 1939, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Cahan, Abraham: Testimonial Dinner, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- California CIO: Constitution and Merger Drafts, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Call Institute: Board of Directors Minutes, Bulletin, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Camp Midvale: Biographies, Clippings, Maps, 1934-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Cardoza, Enio: Correspondence (R. Blackwell, Spanish language), Jun 11, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Carey, James B.: Correspondence (with John Afros, Director, Rand School), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Central Labor Union, New York City: Invitation to Address Mass Meeting re: Haymarket Riot Convictions, Oct 18, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Chase, John C.: Research Materials, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Citizens' Committee for the Defense of American-Mexican Youth: Case Summary, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Cleveland Youth Forum: Press Releases, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Cointelpro: New Left and Black United Front File, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Cole, Margaret: Correspondence (Martin Koppell), 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Colon, Jesus: Correspondence (Lupe Gallardo, Spanish language), Jun 14, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The Coming Nation: Correspondence (A. M. Simons, Julius Gerber), Oct 1911 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Columbia [University] Students for a Democratic Society, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 18A)
- Committee for Non-Violent Revolution: Bulletins, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Committee on Inter-American Relations: "Study of Communist and Socialist Doctrine with Particular Reference to Latin American Countries" (typescript), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Committee on Science and Freedom: Statement on Hungary, Dec 4, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Committee to End the War in Vietnam at State University of New York-Albany, "An Open Letter to President Collins" in the Objector, Dec 4, 1967; 2014.092 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Commons, John R.: Correspondence (to Richard T. Ely), "American Shoemakers, 1648-1895: a Sketch of Industrial Evolution" (typescript, 21 leaves), Jan 14, 1909, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Commonwealth Federation of New York: Third Party Conference Invitation, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Communist Party of the USA: New York State Convention, "Victory Review" (skit by Fairplay Cultural Group), [c. 1943] (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Conference for Progressive Labor Action: Convention Report, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Congress of Industrial Organizations: Letter, James B. Carey to Boris I. Nicolaevsky), Mar 3, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Consumers Union: Memorandum on Communist Affiliation, Oct 22, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Continental Congress of Workers and Farmers for Economic Reconstruction: Bulletins, Minutes, Press Releases, Resolutions, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Convict Labor: Contracts and Testimonies, 1911-1923 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Cooper Union: Mass Meeting Flyer, Feb 18, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Co-operative League: Correspondence (correspondents include Julius Gerber, Albert Sonnichsen), 1911-1912 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Cornell, Frederic: Correspondence, Interviews and Manuscripts, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Cornell, Frederic: "History of the Rand School" (Ph.D. Dissertation), 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Cowley, Robert: "The State vs. William D. Haywood" ( Tamiment Institute Bulletin), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Crook, Wilfrid H.: Correspondence (Stephen Naft), 1928 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Crosswaith, Frank (Negro Labor Committee): Correspondence (National Sharecropper's Week), 1940 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Dagan, Irv: Clippings and Manuscripts, 1936-1937, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Dan, Fydor: Manuscripts (Russian language), 1943 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Dan, Lydia: "Bukharin on Stalin," translated from the Yiddish by Louis Lazarus (typescript, 10 leaves), 1963 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Dana, Charles A.: Correspondence to Karl Marx, re: Articles for Appleton's New American Cyclopedia (photographs and photocopies; from the Institute for Social History, Amsterdam), 1850-1871 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Danish, Max: Remarks at American Labor Press Association Luncheon, Feb 21, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Darling, Joseph F.: Correspondence, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Darrow, Clarence: Centenary, May 1957 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Darrow, Clarence: Letter from a Legal Colleague (carbon copy), May 21, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Darwin, Charles: Letter to Karl Marx (photostat), Oct 13, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Davis, C.W.: "Personal Recollections of "Big Bill" Haywood" (typescript, 16 leaves), undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Debs, Eugene: Letter to New York Call; Letter to Jack Britt Gearity, May 13, 1910, May 20, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Decter, Moshe: "A Short History of the Communist Party of the United States" (typescript, 66 leaves), Apr 1955 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- De Leon, Daniel: Manuscripts about, 1904-1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Dewitt, Samuel A.: Correspondence (Anti-Saloon League of New York, Citizen's Union), Oct 1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Die Zukunft(New York): Correspondence (includes L. Goldberg, Julius Gerber, Abraham I. Shiplacoff), Sep 15, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Dilling, Elizabeth: Miriam Shipley Research File on, 1934-1943 (Box 3, Folder 3a)
- Djilas, Milovan: Excerpt from "Anti-Semitism" (article), Dec 14, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Dodd, Bella V. (Attorney): Correspondence (Layle Lane), Jun 28, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Doherty, Robert: Questionnaires, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Dred Scott Case: Clippings from Coast Seamens Journal, May 26, 1897 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Dubinsky, David: Correspondence (Rand School of Social Science), Dec 16, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- DuBois, W. E. B.: Socialist Party Resignation Letter, Nov 6, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Dunayevskaya, Raya: "Commentary" (typescript, 10 leaves), undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Eastman, Max (translator): "Gabriliad," by Alexander Pushkin, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Ebenstein, Morris: Research Materials, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Ellis Island Bulletins: Hand-written Newspapers from Palmer Raid Deportees, Russian language (given to Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; photocopies, originals in vault), 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 13, Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Ellis, Havelock: Letter to Henry [Davray?], 1900 (Box 3, Folder 13a)
- Emergency Committee for Strikers' Relief: Appeals, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Engels, Fredrick: Correspondence (outgoing; photocopies), 1886-1893 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Eversley, Lord (George Shaw-Lefevre): Correspondence, Jul 1914 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Federal Council of the Churches of Christ in America Committee on Marriage and Home: Minutes, Ideals of Love and Marriage(report), Jan 30, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Federated Press: Sacco-Vanzetti Press Releases, undated (Box 3, Folder 17a)
- Fehrenbatch, John (International Union of Machinists and Blacksmiths): Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Feigenbaum, William M.: Correspondence (incoming; tributes to Algernon Lee), 1923, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Ferry, Elinor: Correspondence and Notes, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Fifth Avenue Vietnam Peace Parade Committee: Correspondence (letters of protest and resignation), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Fine, Emily B.: "High Lights of Socialist Convention" (typescript, 6 leaves), 1932 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Fine, Nathan: Correspondence and Manuscripts, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Fischer, Ruth: "The Year of Great Change" (typescript, 59 leaves, draft chapter of Stalin and Europe), Apr 20, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Fish, Hy (Organizer, Young People's Socialist League and Socialist Party): Personal Papers, 1929-1936 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Fitch, John A.: "Lost Labor Leaders" (typescript, 2 leaves) and Associated Correspondence, Aug 3, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (Manager, Provincetown Playhouse): Correspondence (incoming and outgoing; includes Arthur Leonard Ross, Eugene O'Neill), 1925-1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Fleischman, Harry: Correspondence and Manuscripts, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley: "The Truth about the Paterson Strike" (typescript, 25 leaves), Correspondence (to Philip Foner), 1914, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Folsom, Franklin: Correspondence and Research (Unemployed League), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Frank, Julie Meyer: Manuscript (I) ("Labor's Status in Modern Industrial Society," "Stratification of Labor - The Skilled Worker"), undated (Box 3, Folder 30a)
- Frank, Julie Meyer: Manuscript (II) ("The Industrial Worker," "The Common Laborer"), undated (Box 3, Folder 30b)
- Frank, Julie Meyer: Research Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
- French Revolution: Convention Nationale, Comité de Sureté Générale, 2 declarations, signed, 1791 (Box Shared Tamiment 040)
- Fuchs, Emil: Correspondence (New York State Attorney General Charles E. Newton), Nov 14, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 31b)
- Garrison Benson, Helen: Letter to William Lloyd Garrison, Oct 21, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Garson, Barbara: "A Book about Work in America," "U.A.W Convention - 1972" (typescripts) (Box 3, Folder 32a)
- George, Henry: Letter to "My dear Metcalf", Mar 9, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 32b)
- Georgia People's School: "Report on the First Year of the Georgia People's School", Jun 9, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Gerber, G. August (New York State Campaign Committee, Socialist Party): Fundraising Letter, Oct 17, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Gerber, Julius: Correspondence (Morris Hillquit, John L. Chase, Gustav Theimer), Manuscripts, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- German-American Congress for Democracy: "A Declaration of Principles", 1940 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Germany: "Political Aspects of the German Church Struggle" (typescript, 1 leaf), 1934-1945 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Germer, Adolph: "Extract from Report of the Committee of International Executive Board Members in the Re-Hearing of the Matter Contained in the Walsenburg Circular" (typescript, 2 leaves), Jun 1915 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Ghent, W. J.: Correspondence (incoming and outgoing; includes Morris Hillquit, M. Holt), 1911, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Gilman, Charlotte Perkins: "To Labor" (poem), undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Goebel, George H.: Correspondence (correspondents include Norman Thomas, J. E. Arnett, Daniel W. Hoan), 1912-1963 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Goldberg, Louis P.: "Labor Relations under the Wagner Act" (typescript, 60 leaves) and Related Correspondence (Robert F. Wagner, Henry Morgenthau, Jr.), 1947 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Golden, Harry: Correspondence (outgoing), 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)